[Genius Girlfriend]
[Episode 15]
[Class Meeting]
The winter break is from January 20th
to February 28th,
40 days in total.
Every teacher has assigned homework.
[Pursue Knowledge, Seek Truth;
Practice Diligently, Foster Innovation]
Write it down.
For math, 1 workbook
and 10 mock papers.
Oh my gosh.
For Chinese, 10 essays,
[Class Meeting]
10 classical Chinese texts
you must memorize,
and reading notes.
For English,
memorize all the vocabulary lists
for the next semester.
And for science...
[Pursue Knowledge, Seek Truth;
Practice Diligently, Foster Innovation]
Let me remind you,
even though you're only in grade 10,
[Constantly Strive to Become Stronger;
Strive to Be Number One]
high school life goes by in a flash.
Even though we are
in the experimental class,
if you let your guard down
even a little bit,
you'll be the one left behind.
So, class,
cherish this winter break.
Because when you come back
for the new semester,
you will never have
such relaxing days again.
Alright, that's all I have to say.
Be safe on your way home.
[Constantly Strive to Become Stronger;
Strive to Be Number One]
Happy New Year in advance.
What are your plans
for the winter break, guys?
I have no plans. I'm on break.
But the lab isn't on break,
so there's still no one at home.
I'm traveling abroad
with my parents this year.
That's nice.
I'll stay home, read books,
and watch the shop.
That's a bit boring.
What about you, Tang?
Tang?
What are you doing for winter break?
I don't have any plans.
I have an idea.
Since we have so much
winter break homework,
why don't we get the hard part
out of the way first?
Let's spend 5 days
working together
to finish all the homework
within these 5 days.
For the rest of the break,
we can just relax
and have a great time.
Wouldn't that be exciting?
Wouldn't that be awesome?
What do you say? Are you in?
Zhixia.
Are you in?
Sure.
What about you guys? Say something.
I'm in.
Sure.
I won't join you.
I've already planned
my daily study schedule
based on the holidays.
If I finish all my homework today,
I don't know what other tutoring classes
my parents will sign me up for.
I understand.
I totally understand.
Tang,
you can just tag along and benefit.
You definitely have to join.
If you have any questions you don't know,
all these experts will help you out.
It'll be great.
Let's just treat it as studying together.
Okay, then it's settled.
Tang.
What's wrong?
I really can't write anymore.
I'm going home first.
You guys go ahead.
What's wrong with Tingting?
She didn't do well on the exam this time.
Doesn't our school
require you to change classes
if the sum of your 2 total scores
drops out of the top 50 in the grade?
She ranked 49th
in the grade the first time,
and 53rd this time.
So she is at great risk.
Well,
the final ranking of the 2 total scores
also depends on other students.
You can't just compare her scores alone.
So,
Tang Tingting's fate
is no longer in her own hands.
How can she not be anxious?
If you ask me,
there is only one way out now.
God, have mercy.
Let's not mention this
in front of her.
I'm back, Mom.
Zhixia, you're back.
My daughter is back.
Zhixia, come here.
Look who are here.
Your uncle and aunt are here.
Hello, Uncle. Hello, Aunt.
Hello.
Have a seat.
Zhixia,
we haven't seen each other for years.
She's getting prettier.
Have your studies
been tiring you out lately?
Not really.
Zhuangzhuang, don't you recognize
your sister Zhixia?
You two used to play together
a lot when you were kids.
Zhixia.
Your uncle said you've loved snacks
since you were little.
Here, take this bag of snacks
back to your room
and share them with your brother.
Oh, you.
We have all kinds of snacks
in our supermarket.
Why are you being so polite?
We have them in the store. Really.
Sister,
how is the business at your supermarket?
Is it making money?
Not bad. It's enough to get by.
If you ask me,
relying entirely
on a supermarket for a living
is not a long-term solution.
You just haven't reached
the point where you need money.
Think about it.
These two kids
will be going to college soon.
After they graduate,
they'll need to find jobs
and find a partner.
And Zeqiu is a boy.
You'll have plenty of expenses
in the future.
Exactly.
Everything costs money nowadays.
Our generation
is destined to work hard.
We work so hard to earn this money,
isn't it all just to provide
for our family?
Yes.
Just a few days ago,
we went back to our parents' house.
That house
is really unlivable now.
The roof leaks,
and it smells.
We immediately decided
to renovate it.
Then let's make it clear.
However much the renovation costs,
make a list later,
we'll calculate it
and split it half-half.
Sis, why are you telling me this?
Seriously.
That won't do.
As their children,
there's no need to fuss over
who pays more.
That won't do.
We are family, you...
But we still need to be clear about this.
Okay.
We can talk about this later.
Here's my plan for this year.
Since we are going to renovate that house
in a few days,
I want to bring Mom and Dad over
to stay with us for a while.
They can spend the New Year
at my place this year.
My house is big, you see.
You guys can all come over later,
and we'll celebrate the New Year together.
Sure.
Then I'll go there early
on New Year's Eve
and help you guys out.
Why must we wait for the 30th day?
Just go back with us later.
That won't do.
The supermarket needs manpower
during the New Year.
Your brother-in-law and I
will be busy at the supermarket.
Then, how about this?
Let Zhixia and Zeqiu
go back with me first.
I just bought a new computer.
You two can take this chance to relax.
It's a holiday after all.
You can't just study
at home every day, right?
No need, Uncle.
We'll just stay at our own place.
We have a lot of homework,
and it's quiet here.
That's fine.
We have a lot of rooms.
I'll tidy up the biggest one
just for the 3 of you to study in.
That's right.
By then, the 3 of you...
Goodness,
can you stop playing for a moment?
My kid is good
in every other aspect.
But his grades trouble me so.
I was planning
to find him a tutor.
But first, it's expensive.
Second, he won't yield to any.
But with his own cousins,
it's definitely different.
Exactly.
We know each other,
and they'll surely be more responsible
than an outsider, right?
Besides,
with their excellent grades,
helping him with his homework
should be a piece of cake.
You came all the way here
just to say this?
You didn't have to
go through the trouble.
A phone call would have sufficed.
That won't do.
As your uncle,
I have to come pick you up in person.
Uncle,
Lin Zhixia means that
if you had called,
she would have rejected you over the phone
so you wouldn't have
made a trip for nothing.
That's what she means.
What these two mean is,
they have good grades
mostly because they love studying, right?
A good student
is not necessarily a good teacher.
They can't even help each other much.
Uncle,
studying really depends on oneself.
Zeqiu and I just love studying.
I think you should
pay attention to Zhuangzhuang
and find out what his real interests are.
Besides,
we haven't seen each other for so long.
You coming to me
is no different from finding a tutor.
I...
Mom, I'm going to do my homework.
Okay, go ahead.
Eat something.
We've just been chatting.
[Input Text]
[To: No Ordinary Human]
Jiang Yubai, what are you doing?
[Jiang Yubai, what are you doing?]
[To: High-EQ Human]
[Spacing out at home.]
Spacing out at home.
You?
[Spacing out at home. You?]
Son,
you seem to be in a good mood lately.
You're even texting
with a smile on your face.
Am I?
Are you?
I've seen it several times.
Actually,
I wanted to discuss
our plans for the New Year.
What plans?
Your dad
called this morning
and said he bought you
a ticket to Singapore.
I was thinking,
you haven't seen him in years.
Why not go visit him?
He already booked the ticket.
Is this a notice or a discussion?
He hasn't changed at all.
Still the same.
Always putting his own needs first.
When I was young, we followed him,
moving between China and Singapore.
Every time he gave an order,
we had to follow.
At school,
I had to leave as soon as
I made new friends.
Later, I didn't even dare to make friends.
Is that so?
Didn't I gradually realize
this problem too?
So after we divorced,
I decided to bring you back
to a familiar environment.
You've been doing well lately,
which proves my decision was right.
If you don't want to go,
we won't go.
The way your dad does things
is really annoying.
But ultimately,
isn't it because he misses you?
He just wants
to use the New Year as an opportunity
to express his feelings to you.
Mom,
you and Dad
are completely from different worlds.
Besides, he betrayed you back then.
Why do you always speak up for him?
Matters between adults are
often complicated, helpless,
and hard to explain.
Your dad
is certainly not a good husband.
But that does not affect
his sincere love and concern for his son.
Then,
do you want me to go?
Of course, I respect your decision.
But...
I don't want to leave you alone
for the New Year.
You don't have to worry about me.
I haven't seen
your grandparents for a long time either.
So I can take this chance to visit them.
Okay.
Then,
I'll go.
It's a deal.
Okay.
Visit with a good mood.
I'm leaving.
Two relatives showed up uninvited,
it's suffocating.
Do you want to come out and hide?
Nothing good ever happens
when my uncle and aunt show up.
When they were young,
my mom gave my uncle
her opportunity to go to school.
He finished college and became a lawyer,
but when he looked at my mom...
His gaze was full of disdain.
Also, when Zeqiu was little,
he was sick and needed surgery.
My parents couldn't scrape
together enough money,
so they had to borrow from my uncle.
But he said he didn't have a single cent.
And now look at him.
He has the nerve to come to my house
and ask Zeqiu and me
to be free tutors for his son.
So ridiculous.
What's wrong?
It's the first time I've seen you
say so much in one breath.
This kind of thing is exactly what
you vent to good friends about.
I feel much better after saying it.
Do you have any trouble?
You can tell me about it.
I don't think
I have anything to vent about.
That's good.
He
really wanted to be
involved in your growth,
but because his method was wrong,
it got interpreted as control.
You'll understand when you enter society.
He is your family,
a family member who
would never harm you no matter what.
When I was young,
I always looked up to my dad.
He was successful,
capable,
and quite handsome.
He was always
a perfect role model in my heart.
So I never thought that
he would betray my mom one day.
Since that day,
his image in my heart collapsed.
It had a pretty big impact on me.
It was as if all the evidence of beauty
and happiness in my heart disappeared.
Since then, my relationship with him
has become very tense.
Even now, I don't know
how to persuade myself to forgive him.
Today he just booked me
a ticket to Singapore.
But I'm not sure
if I can properly face him
and his new family.
It's also my first time hearing you
say so much in one breath.
Are you feeling better now?
Much better.
Sometimes I think how nice
it'd be if we could
freely choose our family.
Could it be that
we've already been
quietly making choices?
Staying away from people who hurt you,
getting close to the ones who warm you,
and keeping a place in your heart
for the important people.
These actions
are all redefining family.
I want to discuss something with you two.
Your dad and I are going to
your uncle's house for the New Year
to keep your grandparents company.
You two...
I'm not going.
Zhixia.
You guys go.
I'll stay home alone.
Can you cook?
What are you going to eat alone at home?
Leave me the keys to the supermarket,
and I won't go hungry.
No way. You can't just eat those
for the New Year.
You know exactly what
Uncle and Aunt are like.
If it weren't for Mom's sake,
I would have lost my temper long ago
over the demands he made last time.
I also think his demands
were quite unreasonable.
That's why I didn't ask you to go early.
It's just for the New Year.
I want to spend the New Year
with my family.
Those relatives
don't treat us like family.
Why should we treat them like family
and try to please them?
How about this? I'll stay.
I'll cook for you.
Really?
That's great.
Then I can eat
tomato salad, cola chicken wings,
eight-treasure rice,
and braised spare ribs.
Okay, that's enough.
I can't make that many dishes.
As long as we don't go hungry, it's fine.
These two kids.
All right, it's settled then.
Take good care of your sister at home.
Your dad and I will be back
in a few days, okay?
-Okay.
[To: No Ordinary Human]
My parents agreed to let me
not go to my uncle's house.
I can spend the New Year at home
with Zeqiu this year.
[From: No Ordinary Human]
My flight is tomorrow.
Be careful on the way.
Text me when you're there.
Got it.
Dad.
Son, are you on your way?
Your Aunt Wu has already
made the dumplings.
We're just waiting for you.
I'm on my way.
Okay.
Just contact Uncle Kun when you land.
He'll pick you up at the airport.
Jiang Feng, come take a look.
The baby keeps crying.
Wait a minute. I'm on the phone.
Don't cry. Don't cry.
Daddy will be here soon.
Jiang Feng, hurry up.
Be careful on the way.
Tell me what you want to eat.
It's your first time coming to our house.
I just realized my ID isn't with me.
I have to go back.
If I still can't find it,
go on without me.
Hello? Son?
[Passport]
Is it straight?
Yeah, it's pretty straight.
Why do I feel like
the left side is higher?
I actually think the left side is lower.
Really?
Okay.
-Tingting.
-How is it?
-Dad is back.
-Your dad's back.
Dad!
I missed you so much.
What took you so long?
By my calculations,
you should have arrived this morning.
I went
to buy a gift for Tingting.
For me?
More like a gift package. It's huge.
She really is your own.
What is it?
It looks so good.
This color is so nice.
Of course.
Well? Do you like it?
Dad, do you fathers all think that
girls like pink their whole lives?
This is way too pink.
It's perfect for the New Year. So festive.
Look at this color.
You'd look great in it. It's yours.
Well...
I can actually fit in this size.
You'll look great in it.
Very nice.
Tingting,
in Daddy's heart,
haven't you always been a little girl?
Yes.
So, how did your exams go this year?
Don't talk about that during the New Year.
Tingting and I went to make a wish.
They said you shouldn't
keep talking about it,
or it won't come true.
Okay, not another word of it.
Let's cook then.
Hurry up. We were waiting for you.
I'm starving.
I'll go wash my hands.
Honestly.
This one seems okay.
[New Year's Eve dinner]
Leek.
Leak?
[New Year's Eve dinner]
Leek!
Big or small?
A big one.
Aren't you going to slice it?
You didn't tell me to.
If I tell you now, will you slice it?
Forget it.
It's getting burnt, Zeqiu.
Okay, here, take this.
Is this step correct?
Of course it is.
You're not controlling the heat very well.
I'm not controlling the heat well?
It's definitely your problem.
Come on, who was the one
who swore confidently that
we'd never eat instant noodles
for New Year's Eve dinner?
Stop talking. Salt.
Add some salt.
Look for it.
Isn't that too much?
It's fine.
It'll be flavorful and delicious.
Who's gonna eat this?
You, you.
You can have it all.
Coming!
Jiang Yubai?
Lin Zhixia, I'm here to wish you
a Happy New Year's Eve.
You didn't go to Singapore?
Lin Zhixia!
Where did you go?
-Come in.
-Was that salt you passed me?
Yeah.
Everything browned.
I even tasted it.
Why are you here?
I originally came to say hi to Lin Zhixia.
But now I think
I can be more useful.
You know how to fix a wok?
May you have abundance every year.
How about we have hot pot?
Sure.
I'm fine with anything.
I know.
[Shen]
Didn't you tell me that before?
What about next year?
Can you come back next year?
Next year?
I do have a vacation next year.
But it's hard to say.
It depends on the arrangements
at the observation station.
Our family has gotten used to it
after all these years.
Have a good New Year with our son.
Okay.
Hold on a second.
Happy New Year, Dad.
Happy New Year, Son.
I'm hanging up now.
Why are there still
so many people eating out
on New Year's Eve?
Yeah, it's quite normal.
Everyone is getting busier nowadays.
Actually, people have gradually
come to accept having New Year's Eve
dinner at a restaurant.
Is that so?
Why do I feel like...
it's just because someone
doesn't know how to cook?
You were waiting to say that, weren't you?
Waiter.
Hello, how can I help you?
Hello.
What about the 4 extra portions
of dumplings I ordered earlier?
They've been packed for you
-and placed at the reception.
-Okay. Thank you.
You're welcome.
Are you going back to the dorm later?
I have to.
There are quite a few projects
this semester.
Two of my master's students
aren't planning
to go home for the New Year.
And two others
simply couldn't get tickets.
So I'll
bring them some food and check on them.
They are just kids, after all.
Don't worry.
I've made arrangements too.
Tomorrow,
I'll take a proper break
and stay home with you.
Okay?
Okay.
You eat too.
Waiter.
Yes?
Bill, please.
This way to the reception desk.
Okay.
Happy New Year!
May all your wishes come true.
Look at you, sweetie.
You're so good with words.
Thank you, Grandma.
Eat more.
Is it delicious?
Delicious.
Are you happy?
Grandma, give me a big red envelope.
Is that all you're thinking about?
[Contacts]
[Call Lin Zhixia]
Jiang Yubai, to your left.
Left?
Hello, Shen Fuxuan.
Happy New Year's Eve.
We haven't eaten yet.
Me, my brother, and Jiang Yubai.
You're coming too?
Pair of tens.
Anyone want a pair of twos?
Anyone?
Bomb.
Nice!
Hold it.
Four Kings!
Mom, I won again.
I haven't lost all night.
Stick it on.
My face is so clean.
A certain kid
isn't allowed to cry tonight.
I won't cry.
Honey.
I'll definitely win it back next round.
Who is it? Go open the door.
You're cheating.
Who's cheating?
Why are you here?
Uncle, Aunt,
Grandpa, Grandma, Happy New Year.
My mom specially made this stewed meat,
and asked me to bring some to you.
There's some for the Lins too.
I'm bringing it to them later.
Thank your mom for us.
Duan.
Dad, Mom, look at this kid.
He's just a late bloomer.
He wasn't this tall last year.
He's grown now.
Right, Uncle?
I can even dunk this year.
All brawn and no brains.
Watch your mouth.
Duan's grades are much better than yours.
That's right.
How's your dad?
Playing cards at home too?
Yes.
They started playing
right after an early dinner.
All right.
I'll go over and play
a few rounds with your dad later.
Save it.
Did they invite you?
We're practically family.
By the way,
the two kids from the Lin family
didn't go to their grandma's today.
Tingting,
go to the kitchen
and bring them the big bag of snacks
I bought this afternoon.
No need.
They don't lack this kind of stuff.
I'm waiting for the Spring Festival Gala
to watch my idol perform.
Shouldn't we kids hang out too?
Exactly.
Go on, have fun.
Let's go.
Fine.
Grandpa, Grandma,
I'll go hang out for a bit
and come back later.
Bye.
Bye, Uncle, Aunt.
Bye, Grandpa, Grandma.
Have a meatball.
Delicious.
This...
This should be cooked too.
Crab sticks.
Eat it while it's hot.
Thank you.
Potatoes.
Just eat.
Thanks.
Hot, hot!
Someone's knocking.
Who is it this time?
There's someone else?
[Harmony brings prosperity]
It's really lively tonight.
-Happy New Year.
You guys are here.
Come in.
Happy New Year.
-Gotta spend the New Year with you guys.
-Who is it?
Duan Qiyan.
You sneaked out.
-Happy New Year.
Perfect timing. We're eating.
Really?
Jiang, Shen?
Why are you guys here?
-We…
-I...
-I’m bored. I’m here to celebrate.
-Celebrate the New Year, yes.
Let's sit down and talk.
[Harmony brings prosperity]
My dad made braised pork ribs
and stir-fried beef with bamboo shoots.
They're really good.
Mr. Duan's specialty.
Of course.
Is the opening over?
It's over.
Your idol had
a lot of screen time just now.
Duan Qiyan, it's all your fault.
You fell hard on your butt,
and made me miss seeing my idol.
Well, why were you so anxious?
It was because you rushed me
that I fell and bruised my butt,
and you don't even feel sorry for me.
Let me tell you,
the Spring Festival Gala
will be replayed for 3 days.
Don't worry.
Replayed?
I don't care.
Anyway, I've been looking forward
to their performance since
the announcement.
You have to take responsibility for this.
Okay, okay.
Okay, my lady.
I'll set an alarm
and let you know
as soon as the replay starts,
okay?
Fine.
You two, quiet down.
You're so noisy right after you arrived.
Alright, alright,
stop arguing during the New Year.
Are you two kids?
The ones on top are cooked.
You can eat them.
So delicious. Grab some.
Just you.
The beef meatball hit me.
Hit it back.
It's so lively. It's so good.
Originally, for this New Year,
I thought
I'd just spend it with my sister.
But everyone came.
Thanks to Jiang Yubai
for preparing this sumptuous dinner,
and thanks to Duan Qiyan's dad
for contributing two dishes to the table.
It's nothing. You're welcome.
Happy New Year, friends.
-Happy New Year!
Happy New Year!
-Cheers.
Come on, eat up.
The Jin family has produced a top student.
Let's toast to Baihui again.
Come on, cheers!
-Cheers.
-Cheers! Cheers!
Baihui,
you've made us proud.
Thank you, Grandma.
Baihui
inherited her dad's talent for studying.
Jinquan loves to learn.
He had good grades since he was little.
He joined a newspaper
right after graduation
and became a section chief shortly after.
Brother,
don't say that.
Hearing that makes me a bit ashamed.
Up to now,
I'm still just a section chief.
-Why mention that?
-It's understandable.
It's mainly because
he has a scholar's temperament.
He's not the type to fight for things.
Right, Mom?
Of course.
Scheming with those people
is a total waste of my time.
Those people at work
are too short-sighted.
My biggest priority
is education.
On a larger scale,
it's about the prosperity of our family.
[From: Lin Zhixia]
Yes.
Happy New Year, Jin Baihui.
How's your New Year's Eve dinner?
Then we must propose a toast.
Baihui is the top of her grade this year.
[To: Lin Zhixia]
Next, she'll be the top scorer
on the college entrance exam.
Baihui,
you can't slack off.
We are counting on you
to bring honor to our family.
Our Baihui bears a heavy responsibility.
I must drink this glass.
-Cheers.
[To: Lin Zhixia]
Happy New Year.
[Happy New Year, Jin Baihui.
How's your New Year's Eve dinner?]
Baihui.
Put your phone away.
I haven't seen you
toast your elders all night.
What did I tell you?
Then I'll toast everyone.
Grandma.
Happy New Year,
I wish you good health and longevity.
Good, thank you.
Auntie, Uncle,
I wish you success at work
and great fortune.
Thank you.
Dad, Mom,
thank you for your hard work
and dedication.
Happy New Year.
-Happy New Year.
-You’ve grown up.
Baihui is so wonderful.
By the way, Brother,
when are Jindi and her boyfriend
coming back?
The second or third day
of the New Year, I think.
Okay.
Let us know when the time comes,
Sister-in-law.
[Happy New Year]
I'll treat them to a meal,
and we can have another lively gathering.
Yes, let's gather again.
[To: Lin Zhixia]
Okay.
Actually, I'm not happy.
It's the New Year, and my dad
is still scolding me.
My parents are not here.
[From: Lin Zhixia]
The members of Class Break are all here
at my house.
Does the lead singer want to join?
Mom,
I'm full.
I want to go out for a bit.
Where are you going during the New Year?
I'm going out to watch the fireworks.
All the elders are here.
It's the New Year.
Don't scold the child.
-No, Mom.
-No, I'm not scolding her.
Today is the New Year.
Even machines need a rest
after working for a year.
Baihui, go ahead.
Uncle has your back.
-Okay. Go.
-Go.
Sure, go ahead.
Then I'll go.
Happy New Year!
Come back early.
Okay.
Call me if anything happens.
She's such a good kid.
Why are you here?
Perfect timing.
Let's go.
Where to?
Set off firecrackers.
We're lighting sparklers.
Sparklers.
Let's go.
Hurry up.
♪ I'm like the gentle clouds in the sky ♪
♪ Looking forward
to the stop of the night breeze ♪
♪ I'm wandering about carefully,
looking for the answer ♪
♪ The meteors fly past,
silencing thoughts ♪
♪ Please, give me some clues ♪
♪ I hope you can see through
my situation and confusion ♪
♪ And save me ♪
♪ Can you hear me? Why won't you answer? ♪
♪ I'm calling you secretly at night ♪
♪ The moon whispers
fond words by my ears ♪
♪ It asks if you're still there
through ups and downs ♪
♪ Am I lying? I answer my own questions ♪
♪ But I've already fallen,
I can't help it, oh ♪
♪ Forgive me for being silly
for you and only you ♪
♪ My desires turn into ocean waves
in my dreams ♪
♪ Can you hear me? Why won't you answer? ♪
♪ I'm calling you secretly at night ♪
♪ The moon whispers
fond words by my ears ♪
♪ It asks if you're still there
through ups and downs ♪
♪ Am I lying? I answer my own questions ♪
♪ But I've already fallen,
I can't help it, oh ♪
♪ Forgive me for being silly
for you and only you ♪
♪ My desires turn into ocean waves
in my dreams, lapping gently ♪
Since everyone
is gathered here today,
let's play a game.
I have a test that's perfect
for us to do right now.
Doing a test on a holiday?
No, it's a psychological test.
You scared me.
Please listen carefully.
Imagine
we have to travel with a group of animals,
specifically a monkey,
a snake, and a bird.
How would you travel with them?
I'll go first.
Sorry.
I'd carry the monkey on my shoulder.
The snake can wrap around the monkey,
and the bird can sit on my head.
Laying eggs on your head.
Let me have a go.
The monkey...
I'd hold the monkey in my arms.
The snake can lead the way,
and the bird can rest on my shoulder.
As for me, anything is fine.
The 3 of them can just follow me.
-I'd hold the monkey's hand.
-You go first.
You go ahead.
Then I'll go first.
I'd hold the monkey's hand
and keep the snake in my pocket.
The bird can just fly along.
That's what I thought too.
What a coincidence.
What about you, Zhixia?
Snakes are a bit dangerous.
I've never touched a monkey before either.
How big is that bird?
Lin Zhixia.
It's just a psychological test.
No need to be so rigorous.
Lin Zhixia.
Just stick to your
final exams from now on.
Stop participating
in these psychological tests.
Okay, let me announce the final results.
Actually,
the monkey represents your partner.
And the snake
is your wealth.
The bird represents your children.
Think about how that applies to you.
Look at me.
I carry my partner on my shoulder.
This is the forbearance
and responsibility
that a mature man
and a true gentleman should have.
Save it.
Look at Jiang Yubai holding the monkey
in his arms.
That's a caring man.
It was just a casual reply.
A caring man and a gentleman
are almost the same.
Almost the same.
Fortunately, I didn't say anything.
We're holding the monkey's hand.
There's nothing wrong with this answer.
-Yes.
-It makes sense.
It's normal.
Why are we all talking about the monkey?
We don't have the rest.
You don't have a monkey either.
We have nothing.
-We have nothing.
-All nothing.
That's right.
Actually, just now,
I just wanted to see our differences.
It turns out you are all the same.
Only Zhixia is different.
-Zhixia.
-Yeah, it makes sense.
Was it fun?
It was a very fun test.
Very fun.
What's in this big jar of yours?
Oh, that's fermented rice wine.
My parents made it.
It's delicious with glutinous rice balls
and eggs.
Fermented rice wine?
It sounds delicious.
Shall we...
♪ Running and waiting for my exploration ♪
♪ The unknown is so fascinating ♪
♪ Young me stood on tiptoes ♪
♪ Everything is transparent;
time is too light ♪
♪ With my deduction,
the answer is clear in an instant ♪
♪ The timer is still counting down
3, 2, 1 ♪
♪ The best answer is within our reach ♪
♪ How should I define ♪
♪ Crossing the distance
between meridians and parallels ♪
♪ With my deduction,
the answer is clear in an instant ♪
♪ The timer is still counting down
3, 2, 1 ♪
♪ The best answer is within our reach ♪
♪ The destined miracle ♪
♪ Crossing the distance
between meridians and parallels ♪
In the new year,
I hope we all
succeed in our studies.
Especially you, Tang.
Hurry up and get into the top 50.
Okay?
We all hope so.
Stop. I've made a wish.
It won't work if you say more.
All we can do now is wait
and wish me well.
Cheers!
-Cheers!
Yes, cheers. Come on.
Come on.
Let me say a word.
I hope in the new year,
everyone can do what they want.
Happiness is the most important!
Cheers.
Happiness for all.
-Cheers.
-Happiness for all.
Then I hope we can always be good friends.
-Good friends.
-Well said, Zhixia.
Let's drink to that.
Nice.
Well said, Zhixia.
Then I hope that in the new year,
everyone can go all out
and get the grades they want.
Cheers.
-Cheers!
Go!
Cheers!
-Cheers!
Go!
Then I won't talk about grades.
I'll talk about something else.
I hope...
He doesn't like listening to you.
What's wrong?
He drank too much fermented rice wine!
So Jiang Yubai has things
he's not good at, too.
This doesn't look good.
What should we do?
How about letting him sleep here tonight?
No.
It's getting late.
I'll take him back.
Okay, you take him back.
Zeqiu, help me.
I'll help you.
Come on, get up.
No need, you sit.
Sit well.
Come on, let me pass.
Careful.
I got it.
Take that suitcase with you.
That's his suitcase.
He can come get it when he wakes up.
No need, I can carry it.
He can carry it.
He's got it.
Jiang Yubai.
Stop pretending.
I know you're not drunk.
Jiang Yubai.
Did you gain weight
during the winter break?
Wake up!
If you don't wake up, I'm leaving.
You are so annoying!
The living room was so small back then,
but it held everyone's laughter.
The sweetness of the fermented rice wine
seemed to still linger on our tongues,
and the colors of the fireworks
were reflected in our tears of joy.
I remember my friends and I
listening to the lively TV programs,
clinking glasses clumsily,
and feeling the warmth
of the word "reunion."
It turns out
when the bonds of blood
aren't warm enough,
Heaven still allows us
to choose our own family.
That would be friends.
We don't share the same last name,
but we remember each other's preferences.
We've seen each other at our worst
and shared our brightest moments.
The precious New Year mood
is about guarding simple happiness
with the family you choose.
The glass is full.
The glass is empty.
I really want to raise my glass again,
clink it gently against the void,
and toast once more to
the winter that made us a family.